idebate.org 2018-08-29

# Privacy Policy | idebate.org

Privacy Policy

The International Debate Education Association [IDEA, including individual IDEA entities and the IDEA Network] is committed to safeguarding your privacy. All IDEA and IDEA-affiliated websites adhere to a rigid policy for ensuring the privacy of any personally identifiable information [name, mailing address, email address, occupation, etc.] that may be collected though our websites.

### Collecting Information

IDEA gathers email addresses from users who contact IDEA for general information purposes or subscribe to our electronic mailing lists for newsletters and other publications or use services like T-Bate (Text Debate) or the internal community discussion boards. We may also collect other personal information, including mailing address and occupation, from users who choose to send such information by email.

The IDebate website will only collect personally identifiable information from you if you voluntarily supply it. IDEA is the sole owner of and the only organization that uses the information collected on this website. _**We do not sell, share, or rent information under any circumstances**_. Subject to the following sentences, IDEA will not disclose personally identifiable information without first receiving your permission. IDEA may disclose information about its users if required to do so by law or in its good-faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. IDEA may also disclose information about its users to law enforcement officers or others, in its good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms & Conditions; respond to claims that any posting or other content violates the rights of third-parties; or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of, as appropriate, IDEA, its users, or the general public.

### Tracking and Cookies

IDEA collects non-personal information [IP addresses and login information] from visitors to help us understand how our site is being used. Like most websites, the IDEA site may place a "cookie," or small file, in the browser of a visitor's computer. This cookie will assign a user a unique number that allows IDEA to save information so that the information does not need to be re-entered. At no time will this cookie reveal to others any information whatsoever.

### Security

IDEA's IT team is woking every day to keep the site security at the highest level according to the newest IT standards and trends. Our team also ensures and takes care of the data provided to the site so it can be open, clear and always available to the users. We have a complete overview of the internal data handling workflows within the organisation represented by the website. An experienced legal adviser is consulted by our organisation through this transformation process.

IDEA's site allows users to cancel their own user account at any time and are able to request removal of all their personal data. All of the needed features such as Cookie policy are already implemented. User are informed when our site uses cookies to collect data.
